Inventory of the Floyd Halleck Higgins Photographs of Mexican Sugar Beet Workers
Department of Special Collections
Floyd Halleck Higgins Photographs of Mexican Sugar Beet Workers
1942
Higgins, Floyd Halleck, 1886-1975.
0.8 linear feet; 196 prints and negatives 135 digital images
Floyd Halleck Higgins was born on May 15, 1886, in Keokuk, Iowa. After graduating from Iowa State College in Ames, he moved to Chicago and western Canada to work in a variety of public relations positions including Director of Public Relations, National Association of Farm Equipment Manufacturers (1922-1926). Higgins moved to California in 1927 where he became the News Editor for Caterpillar Tractor Company. In 1933, when Caterpillar moved its corporate headquarters to Peoria, Illinois, Higgins chose to stay in California where he worked as a free-lance writer. His articles appeared in Pacific Rural Press, Farm Implement News, Diesel Progress, Rice Journal, and other agricultural journals. In 1942, Higgins took photographs of Mexican workers entering the United States "brought in for the [sugar] beet harvest" for California Fields Crops, Inc. and as Higgins explains in a letter that he tried "to catch a lot of the social side in pictures." The photographs were taken mainly in the agricultural areas of the California communities of Woodland, Pleasanton, Manteca, and Salinas.
University of California, Davis. General Library. Dept. of Special Collections. Davis, California 95616-5292
D-494
Biography
Floyd Halleck Higgins was born on May 15, 1886, in Keokuk, Iowa. After graduating from Iowa State College in Ames, he moved to Chicago and western Canada to work in a variety of public relations positions including Director of Public Relations, National Association of Farm Equipment Manufacturers (1922-1926). Higgins moved to California in 1927 where he became the News Editor for Caterpillar Tractor Company. He immediately found that farm machinery history "was gathered by each company's ad men when they needed to get up something for a 'special number' of some publication in which its ads appeared." In self defense, Higgins began collecting materials relating to the origins of combines and tractors but his interests expanded to include all forms of farm mechanization.
In 1933, Caterpillar moved its corporate headquarters to Peoria, Illinois. Higgins chose to stay in California where he worked as a free-lance writer. His articles appeared in Pacific Rural Press, Farm Implement News, Diesel Progress, Rice Journal, and other agricultural journals. He used every opportunity to interview "the men who were there" and create an historical record supported by material in his ever-growing collection.
In 1959, Higgins sold his collection of more than ninety file cabinet drawers of research materials, to the University of California, Davis. The University Library hired him to remain the curator of the collection, a position he held until 1972 when ill health forced him to retire. He died on February 28, 1975.
Scope and Content
This finding aid is for the portion of the collection that is images of Mexican sugar beet workers in California.
In 1942, F. Hal Higgins, a free-lance journalist and Safeway Farm Reporter, was given the job of providing publicity for the Mexican workers coming into California to harvest sugar beets. This was a special, informal program funded by the United States government under the Farm Security Administration. It is considered the beginning of what is now called the Bracero System.
"The spontaneous and irregular migration that prevailed gave way abruptly to one that was supervised and regulated by government." (Merchants of Labor; the Mexican Bracero Story, Ernesto Galarza, 1964). The 3000 Mexican men were carefully selected by the Mexican Government, the United States Government, and California Field Crops, Inc. to harvest the sugar beet crop. The sugar beet crop was especially large and there was a shortage of farm workers due to World War II. Also called Stoop Laborers, or Good Neighbor workers by Higgins, the Mexican workers came to top and harvest sugar beets.
Mexican Nationals in California Agriculture 1942-1959, California Department of Employment, 1959, states, "World War II created conditions and demands which seriously depleted California's farm manpower resources at a time when farmers were being called upon to augment production of food and fiber to maintain civilian and military life...Early in 1942, California farmers faced a critical labor shortage…Sugar beet growers made the first World War II request for Mexican labor..."
Higgins explained in a letter that he tried "to catch a lot of the social side in pictures." In Photographing Farmworkers in California, author Richard Steven Street states that "Higgins followed the braceros out into the countryside, creating a highly original essay on the vanguard of a labor program that would eventually entice one out of every nine Mexican men north." The photographs show many aspects of the workers lives: arriving by train, building of the labor camps, dining and entertainment, and working in the fields. The photographs were taken mainly in the agricultural areas of the California communities of Woodland, Clarksburg, Manteca, Pleasanton, and Salinas. The descriptions contained in some entries were made by F. Hal Higgins.
Arrangement of the Collection
Arrangement of the collection is in 4 series, Mexican workers arrive in the United States, Labor camp construction, Life in the labor camps, and Harvesting the sugar beets.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Higgins, Floyd Halleck, 1886-1975--Archives.; Migrant Agricultural Laborers--California--Pictorial works; Sugar beet industry --California--History--20th Century; Historic Buildings--California--Spreckels--Pictorial works; Documentary Photography--California; Spreckels Sugar Company
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired from F. Hal Higgins with generous assistance from the International Harvester Company, Deere & Company, and Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, 1959.
- Mexican workers arrive in the United States, 1942; Series 1.; 25 prints and negatives
  Mexican workers began arriving in 1942, by informal agreement with the Mexican and United State Government. They arrived by train and were bused to their labor camps.
  - Southern Pacific train, SP1275, at station with Mexican workers looking out of window, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0001; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Mexican workers standing in front of bus. The bus, in background, is labeled Pacific Greyhound Line, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0003; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Mexican workers standing in front of bus. The bus, in background, is labeled Pacific Greyhound Line, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0004; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 6 x 13 cm. (Box-folder 1:1)
    "Mexican national laborers arrive at Salinas, California." Description by Hal Higgins. (Photo is cropped. The bus, in the background, does not appear.)
  - A large group of Mexican workers walking down a street with a police escort, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0007; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Mexican workers entering Roberts Union Farm Center, [San Joaquin County], view from left of Center, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0011; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Mexican workers entering Roberts Union Farm Center, [San Joaquin County], view from front of Center, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0012; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 16 cm. (Box-folder 1:1)
    "Hot lunch for the newly-arrived Mexicans helps the Good Neighbor idea as they arrive to work at beet topping and loading in California. Mexican officials and U.S. Government men as well as leaders in the beet sugar industry welcomed them on their Mexican workers arrival." Description by Hal Higgins.
  - Mexican workers entering Roberts Union Farm Center, [San Joaquin County], view from left of Center, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0013; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 15 x 13 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Mexican workers getting out of truck at Roberts Union Farm Center, [San Joaquin County], 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0014; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 16 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Two men with a group of Mexican workers standing near Southern Pacific train, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0015; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 16 cm. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Ten Mexican workers standing near trucks, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0016; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - One Mexican worker getting into truck, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0017; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - One Mexican worker getting into truck, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0018; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 14 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Mexican workers standing in front of a bus with some men on right moving away from photographer, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0019; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Mexican workers getting off train, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0020; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Mexican workers with Government Officials by Railway Express Agency station, Salinas, California, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0022; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Mexican workers departing from train station by bus, Salinas, California, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0023; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Last group of Mexican workers departing from train station by bus, Salinas, California, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0024; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Government Official with Mexican workers, 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0026; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Mexican workers in Galt Unified School District school bus, 1942; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0071; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 16 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Three men standing outside the Roberts Union Farm Center, [San Joaquin County], 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0110; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 16 cm. (Box-folder 1:1)
    "Chief Agriculturalist of the Holly Sugar Corp., Charles Lavis, center, with Mexican officials as they talk over the Good Neighbor policies involved in handling the 3,000 imported Mexican workers as the first trainload arrives at Stockton, Calif. On Sept 29." Description by Hal Higgins.
  - Mexican workers outside the Roberts Union Farm Center, [San Joaquin County], 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0111; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 17 cm. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Three men, one of them, Chief Agriculturalist of the Holly Sugar Corp., Charles Lavis, center standing outside the Roberts Union Farm Center, [San Joaquin County], 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0112; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 16 cm. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Three men, one of them, Chief Agriculturalist of the Holly Sugar Corp., Charles Lavis, center standing outside the Roberts Union Farm Center, [San Joaquin County], 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0113; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 17 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Three men standing next to two Holly Sugar Corp. trucks, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0114; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 17 cm. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Mexican workers standing outside the Roberts Union Farm Center [San Joaquin County], 1942 Sept.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0115; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Labor camp construction, 1942; Series 2.; 31 prints and negatives
  "Labor camps construction and refurbishing was completed before the first workers arrived. Some labor camps were old Japanese Relocation camps. There were wash houses, dining halls, and sleeping quarters." Description by Hal Higgins.
  - Four workers entering camp building, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0075; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
    "Mexican Sugar Beet Laborers, Weyl-Zuckerman Ranch, Stockton, Cal. Labor Camp Construction" Description by Hall Higgins.
  - Four workers entering camp building, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0076; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Carpenters building a camp building, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0077; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
    "Camp Construction for Mexican Sugar Beet Workers, Rindge Tract, Weyl-Zuckerman Ranch, Stockton, California." Description by Hal Higgins.
  - Carpenters building a camp building, two men looking on, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0078; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - View of labor camp buildings from afar, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0079; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - View of labor camp construction of buildings with scrap wood pile, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0080; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - View of labor camp construction of buildings with scrap wood pile, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0081; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
    "Camp Construction for Mexican Sugar Beet Workers, Rindge Tract, Weyl-Zuckerman Ranch, Stockton, California." Description by Hall Higgins.
    c.1
  - Seven Carpenters working on a building in labor camp, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0082; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Two labor camp buildings with a man standing in front of the buildings, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0083; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - One man in front of labor camp buildings, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0084; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Several Mexican workers at wash basin in labor camp, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0085; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - One labor camp building with a man standing nearby, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0086; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - View of labor camp construction of buildings with scrap wood pile, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0091; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
    "Old Jap[anese] labor camp all cleaned up, whitewashed and new carpentering to enclose wash stands and more showers with hot water at a beet labor camp in the San Joaquin Valley of California." Description by Hal Higgins.
    c.2
  - Mexican worker washing himself, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0092; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
    "Hot water for baths is important in the housing plans for Mexican workers. Here is a typical Mexican of the new Mexican workers arrivals enjoying his bath just before dinner immediately on Mexican workers arrival at his camp. Many camps have enlarged and improved their bathing and washing facilities for their beet field workers. Spreckels Sugar Company, Mexican workers, Spreckels, California." Description by Hall Higgins.
  - Mexican worker washing himself, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0093; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
    "Spreckels Sugar Company, Mexican workers, Spreckels, California." Description by Hal Higgins.
  - Mexican worker washing himself, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0094; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Housing at Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland California, Nov., 1942; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0119; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 10 x 14 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Housing at Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland California, Nov., 1942; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0120; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Cookhouse at Spreckels Sugar Company, Salinas Valley, California, 1942; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0121; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 14 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
    "More than $100,000 in new buildings, carpentry, screens, paint, whitewash and plumbing went into Mexican beet field labor camps up and down the state to make the Good Neighbor workers more comfortable. Here is scene at the cookhouse of the Spreckels Sugar Company, Spreckels, Salinas Valley." Description by Hal Higgins.
  - Cookhouse at Spreckels Sugar Company, Salinas Valley, California, 1942; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0122; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 14 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
    "Carpenters at work rehabilitating the old Spreckels Sugar Company labor camp dining hall near the world's largest sigar [sic] beet factory in the Salinas Valley. New screening, paint, electric lights, plumbing, etc. were installed, checked or put in good working order for the workers arriving from Mexico City." Description by Hal Higgins.
  - Five Mexican workers standing in front of labor camp buildings, Salinas, California, 1942; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0123; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 14 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
    "At Spreckels where the largest beet sugar factory in the world is located, arriving beet field workers from Mexico found everything whitewashed and cleaned up with new screens on the cookhouse and much carpentering and painting being done to improve housing and food sanitation." Description by Hal Higgins.
  - One man working on labor camp building at Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland California, 1942 Nov. 24; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0124; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 11 x 17 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
  - One man working on labor camp building at Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland California, 1942 Nov. 24; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0125; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - One man walking among the labor camp buildings at Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland California, 1942 Nov. 24; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0126; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 11 x 16 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Five labor camp buildings at Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland California, 1942 Nov. 24; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0154; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Man with wheelbarrow in front of labor camp buildings, 1942 Nov. 24; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0155; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Labor camp buildings at Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland California, 1942 Nov. 24; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0156; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Three men building a small building at a labor camp, Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland California, 1942 Nov. 24; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0157; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 9 x 15 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Three men building a small building at a labor camp, Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland California, 1942 Nov. 24; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0158; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Labor camp buildings at Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland California with fields in foreground, 1942 Nov. 24; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0159; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:2)
    "Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland [California] Building new housing for Mexican sugar beet workers 11-42." Description by Hal Higgins.
  - Labor camp buildings at Spreckels Sugar Company, Woodland California with fields in foreground, 1942 Nov. 24; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0160; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm (Box-folder 2:2)
- Life in the labor camps, 1942; Series 3.; 57 prints and negatives
  Mexican workers were housed in labor camps, some of which were located near Spreckels Sugar Plants in Woodland, and Salinas. There were washing facilities, cooking facilities, entertainment and church services.
  - Mexican workers standing in front of church., 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0002; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Mexican workers crossing street to enter church, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0005; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Mexican workers walking away from church, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0006; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Mexican workers seated in an assembly room, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0008; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 14 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Mexican workers seated in an assembly room, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0009; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 14 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Mexican workers seated in an assembly room, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0010; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 14 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
    c.3
  - Government officials standing in front of church with police escort, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0021; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Mexican workers entering church with priest at door, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0025; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Mexican workers leaving church, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0027; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Two women holding Mexican and American flags with audience, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0028; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Two women holding Mexican and American flags with audience, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0029; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 12 x 16 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Two women holding Mexican and American flags, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0030; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Two women holding Mexican and American flags, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0031; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 14 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Woman dancing on a Mexican hat, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0032; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Woman dancing on a Mexican hat, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0033; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
    "Mexican nationals imported to U.S. for sugar beet harvest in World War II were entertained in public theaters by artists of their own nationality in programs prepared and put on by the sugar beet industry." Description by Hal Higgins.
  - Woman singing at microphone, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0034; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Woman singing at microphone, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0035; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Two women dancing, one on a Mexican hat, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0036; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Two women dancing, one on a Mexican hat, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0037; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Three women entertainers facing camera, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0038; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 10 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Three women entertainers facing camera, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0039; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Three women entertainers facing camera, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0040; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Three women entertainers facing camera, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0041; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
    c.4
  - Three women entertainers facing camera, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0042; 1 photograph: acetate negative: 13 x 19 cm. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Five women entertainers facing camera, 1942 Oct.; UCD.PIC.D494.2009.0043; 1 photograph: Gelatin Silver Print DOP: 13 x 18 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)